<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Tsai Ming-liang | 软醉]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.softdrunk.me/blog/categories/tsai-ming-liang/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.softdrunk.me/"/>
  <updated>2015-05-03T14:24:39-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.softdrunk.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Yue Tian (Alex)]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Indulgence Without Dialogues in Tsai Ming-Liang’s Vive L’Amour]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.softdrunk.me/blog/2015/05/03/indulgence-without-dialogues-in-tsai-mingliangs-vive-lamour/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-03T14:12:37-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.softdrunk.me/blog/2015/05/03/indulgence-without-dialogues-in-tsai-mingliangs-vive-lamour</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/vivelamour.jpg" width="1024" height="658" title="‘Vive L’Amour’" ></p>

<p>Tsai Mingliang’s award-winning piece <em>Vive L’Amour</em> is deemed as a slow film by
many. Without much effort, one can find a series of scenes where not much is
happening and the conversations between characters are kept at its minimum.
Though this sort of hyperbolic realism without dialogues that brings the
viewers’ attention to the realism itself risks making them feel utterly
uncomfortable and may thus find this way of storytelling unappealing, it does
provide the characters in the film with sequences of uninterrupted indulgence in
emotional expression, bringing the audiences’ attention to the film’s theme of
loneliness.</p>

<p>In some scenes of the film, no dialogues are involved in order to represent the
character’s self-indulgent and introvert personality. Take Xiao Kang for
example, after he successfully stole the saleswomen’s key to the apartment, he
often spends time by himself in the apartment doing a variety of things for
entertainment. For instance, there are several occasions of him sank in the bath
tub. There is also another scene where he personifies a watermelon and kisses it
before finally eating it. And yet another one where he puts on the clothes of
the saleswoman and acts as a female. These scenes that feature minimal dialogues
not only add a hilarious twist to the serious discussion of urban alienation in
the film, but also builds up a concrete character who indulges in
self-entertainment, sadly because of loneliness resulted from his incapability
of expressing himself to others.</p>

<p>While in some other occasions where both the characters are capable of
expressing themselves, they ironically choose not to. Although the lack of
dialogues and communications may help these characters indulge in their actions,
          they at the same time point the audiences to the poignant fact that
          the indulgence is only physical, without any spiritual enjoyment. The
          two sexual scenes in the film illustrate my point well. The first time
          when the sidewalk vendor first meets the saleswoman, he walks her back
          to the apartment without any dialogues. Their mutual understanding
          precisely reveals that the void of words is intentional on both sides.
          When they are indulged in sex, the sound is completely taken over by
          their heavy breathes, making the audience conscious of the fact that
          all they are doing is only fulfilling each other’s physical desire.</p>

<p>In the crying scene that ends the film, no dialogues are used so that the
saleswoman can share her emotions publicly but still keep private of the events
that happened to her. The fact that she can only express her emotions publicly
because she is so lonely that there is no one who listens to her, and yet she
cannot express herself through words because her secret would then be exposed is
such a grief irony. It is precisely the void of dialogue that highlights the
saleswoman’s strong wish for her indulgence in a self expression.</p>

<p>These sequences of scenes that feature minimal conversations in them demonstrate
Tsai’s creative use of non-dialogic representations of character personalities,
  lack of spiritual exchanges, and the necessity of public expression because of
  loneliness. Although the lack of dialogues in these sequences have varied
  connotations, they all provide the characters the possibility of
  self-indulgence and bring the spectators’ attention to the alienated urban
  lifestyle.</p>

<hr />
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
